SEAN NEDEN

CONTACT

sean.neden.name

602.703.0820

y cannuk

in seanneden

cannuk

SKILLS

Javascript

Backbone

MvSOL

AJAX

Git

Ruby on Rails

User Experience

SQL

RSpec

CoffeeScript

Test Driven Development

MVC (Front and Back end)

Marionette

SUMMARY

An experienced Software Engineer with a focus on Development for the web. I have experience in back end, front end and full stack roles. I have worked in companies from start-up to enterprise. I am a consistent, product focused engineer with an entrepreneurial spirit.

EMPLOYMENT

Curriculet

Lead Engineer Oct 2012 to Current

As Curriculet's first engineer, I have been involved in most of the Engineering related functions of the company.

- The first Engineer hired by Curriculet (employee number 3)
- Responsible for architecting and creating the core Curriculet eBook reading experience, a fundamental piece of Curriculet's product.
- Architected, directed and helped create the front end of all of Curriculet's features.
- Authored and maintained policies around hiring, code reviews, testing and other engineering policies.
- Participated in 2 week customer support rotations involving direct contact with customers via phone and email.

Pipewise

Senior Engineer

lun 2012 to Oct 2012

An innovative CRM built with Ruby on Rails, CoffeeScript and Backbone I worked as a full stack engineer with an emphasis on front end development.

- Created a streamlined onboarding interface to lead new users through their initial experience within the app
- Worked with the Product manager to design the new automated email campaign feature. Took ownership of creating most of the feature functionality also.

GoDaddy.com

Senior Software Developer

Mar 2011 to lun 2012

- A developer on Website Tonight (a WSIWYG website builder), I created an HTML5 (Canvas) Image editing
 solution which allows users to edit images within the browser. Edit functionality includes crop, re-size, rotate,
 color adjustments (hue, saturation), and contrast adjustment as well as adding and manipulating text. Image
 edits are shown in the browser in real time.
- Worked to move an existing and legacy Javascript code base to a modern modular design using Backbone and Require. Created documentation to help other developers transition to the new pattern.
- Coordinated deployments between Windows operations, and QA teams for a product with 900,000 users.
- Participated in on call activities, troubleshooting and resolving direct customer issues.
- Created internal developer tools to monitor data center network problems and automate previously
 manual processes.

Black, Gould & Associates

Senior Software Developer

Aug 2010 to Mar 2011

- Updated an existing web based Health Insurance rater product to focus on the user experience. Refactored from a traditional web form based solution to an entirely Javascript/ client side solution.
- Created an application wide theme editor which allowed users to change the look and feel of the application through a simple color picker and a real time view of the changes.

Oce Reprographic Technologies

Software Engineer

Feb 2004 to Aug 2010

- Technical Lead for a document distribution web application designed around the ASP.NET MVC framework, and the Dojo JavaScript Toolkit. Responsible for the majority of the design and architecture of the user interface and the C#/ ASP.NET backend.
- Lead Web Developer maintaining an existing project/document management web application with heavy use
 of JavaScript, AJAX, XML and XSL.
- Creation of several advanced developer tools including a Database Mocking layer and Unit testing integration.

Business Integration Group

Software Developer

May 2002 to Feb 2004

- Developed a web based Gantt chart allowing drag and drop editing of tasks using JavaScript and AJAX techniques.
- Developed and designed a complete document management solution allowing document sharing, uploading, versioning, etc. Solution was entirely web based and utilized extensive JavaScript.
- Developed a customizable user portal to the Business Integration Group application, which allowed the user
 to create links and views to information they used the most.

EDUCATION

DeVry University
Bachelors Computer Information Systems 2004